<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build Your Own GPU Workstation</title>
      <link>/blog_posts/workstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog_posts/workstation/</guid>
      
        <description>As machine learning researchers, sometimes we may have the need to have our own GPU workstation. Along with the recent trend of WuKong, I built a 4090 GPU workstation. The total amount excluding the price of GPU is around 1800 before tax.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write High-quality Code</title>
      <link>/blog_posts/codewriting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog_posts/codewriting/</guid>
      
        <description>Some Experience to Share For Writing Good Code During my experience of researching and doing projects, I believe it is always very helpful to manage good code. Clear code with good annotations will help us complete projects and develop products more smoothly.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepare Your Application for CS PhD.</title>
      <link>/blog_posts/csphdapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog_posts/csphdapp/</guid>
      
        <description>Catalog Catalog Before You Read Let&amp;rsquo;s Start Introduction Before Application What do I mean by managing research? Why do you need papers? The Application Connection Reference Letter Research Experience Publications Choosing programs and professors CV Meeting Slides Personal History Statement SOP/PS/RP Writing a PS Paragraph 1 Paragraph 2-4 Last two paragraphs GPA Research Internship TOFEL/GRE Connecting Professors via Email After Application Contact Me Previous students advised Before You Read This will be a long article which will take you approximately about 15 minutes to read.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      
        <description>I believe having a good code repo is a necessary part of a good paper. You can find the source code for my papers and other interesting projects through my Github.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo Gallery</title>
      <link>/gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/gallery/</guid>
      
        <description>&amp;#x1f48f; With my beloved beautiful girl, Ziqi Li. &amp;#x2b50; With Professor Baochun Li, Professor Vincent Wong, and members of iQua on 2024 Engineering Institute of Canada (EIC) Gala.
&amp;#x1f4f7; by Mitch Lenet</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      
        <description>You can learn more about my papers through Google Scholar and OpenReview.
Privacy-Preserving Machine Learning Hengyuan Xu, Liyao Xiang, Hangyu Ye, Dixi Yao, Pengzhi Chu, Baochun Li. &amp;ldquo;Permutation Equivariance of Transformers and Its Applications&amp;rdquo; in Proceedings of The IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition 2024 (CVPR), Seattle, USA, Jun 17 - Jun 21, 2024.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>