<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>我在多大读研究生的二三事--苏学姐篇--卷一</title>
      <link>/stories/ningxin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/stories/ningxin/</guid>
      
        <description>前言 小y曾在多伦多大学读硕士研究生。这篇“小故事集”讲的是小y和同组的苏学姐之间发生的几件趣事。原本这些都不算什么大事，小y也没打算提，但因为小y曾在社交媒体“小红书”上一条帖子下留过一句不到十个字的评论（帖子现已删除），结果却引得苏学姐在微信上大发雷霆。她发来一长串莫名其妙的话（稍后详述），大意是指责小y“造谣”，还说那条评论影响了她招生。好吧，既然如此，小y就借本文把当时评论展开说说。是真是假，读者诸君自有判断。如果真是无稽之谈，不攻自破便是。注意：鉴于网络并非法外之地，文中小y只会叙述自己亲身经历的事情，听说来的传闻一律不写。
好客之道 初来导师的课题组时，小y举目无亲，人生地不熟。热情好客的苏学姐便邀约小y去聚会联谊。在另一位同学的阳台上，一群研究生难免一起吐槽起导师。期间小y感叹了一下多伦多这地方房租离谱，系里发的补助根本不够花。没想到苏学姐告诉我，在她刚来多伦多的时候，她是住在导师家的。导师和家人住在house楼上，苏学姐住在地下室，苏学姐还顺便吐槽说导师工作太忙，晚饭老吃鸡胸肉。
众望所归 我们导师是联邦学习（federated learning）领域的大牛，还主导开发了一个非常好用的开源框架 Plato。这个框架能高效模拟联邦学习中客户端的并行训练，并且实现了许多不同的FL算法。苏学姐的主要研究方向之一就是联邦学习，并是一篇发表在 ACM TURC 会议上的论文的共同作者。那篇论文的一作是导师，Plato的大部分核心代码都是导师敲出来的心血结晶。而论文的二作正是苏学姐。不过我看了下 Plato 代码仓库的贡献排行榜，导师的贡献断崖式第一毋庸置疑，苏学姐的贡献度排第九位，只有10 次commit。
题外话：苏学姐的研究兴趣相当广泛，发表论文涉猎metaverse, async federated learning, unlearning, large model.
不耻下问 片段一 苏学姐有时也会向小y这个后辈讨教学术问题。印象中有两次：一次她问我有没有现成的 Matplotlib 画图脚本（比如画柱状图、散点图之类）。小y心想，学姐你之前发论文里的图表难道不是用代码画的？便好奇反问：“学姐，你以前论文里的图都是怎么弄的呀？” 没料到苏学姐回答：“就用 keynote 画。” 小y之后默默分享给她一个前辈整理的画图脚本。事后小y特意翻了翻苏学姐以前的论文，那里面的图怎么看都不像是 Keynote 里手工画出来的。</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepare for CELPIP Test</title>
      <link>/blog_posts/celpip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog_posts/celpip/</guid>
      
        <description>A Necessary Condition of Post Graduate Work Permit (PGWP) and Immigration in Canada In the last year, IRCC implemented the policy that to get PGWP, a graduated student must obtain English test at level of CLB 7 or higher.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open a Start-Up</title>
      <link>/blog_posts/openbusiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog_posts/openbusiness/</guid>
      
        <description>Start a Start-Up Last year, I started my own business Hemlig AI and fortunately, we successfully got some investors who have interest in our products. Apart from that, we also sell our plans to preserve privacy and earn some money in 2024.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Your Own GPU Workstation</title>
      <link>/blog_posts/workstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog_posts/workstation/</guid>
      
        <description>As machine learning researchers, sometimes we may have the need to have our own GPU workstation. Along with the recent trend of WuKong, I built a 4090 GPU workstation. The total amount excluding the price of GPU is around 1800 before tax.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write High-quality Code</title>
      <link>/blog_posts/codewriting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog_posts/codewriting/</guid>
      
        <description>Some Experience to Share For Writing Good Code During my experience of researching and doing projects, I believe it is always very helpful to manage good code. Clear code with good annotations will help us complete projects and develop products more smoothly.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepare Your Application for CS PhD.</title>
      <link>/blog_posts/csphdapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog_posts/csphdapp/</guid>
      
        <description>Catalog Catalog Before You Read Let&amp;rsquo;s Start Introduction Before Application What do I mean by managing research? Why do you need papers? The Application Connection Reference Letter Research Experience Publications Choosing programs and professors CV Meeting Slides Personal History Statement SOP/PS/RP Writing a PS Paragraph 1 Paragraph 2-4 Last two paragraphs GPA Research Internship TOFEL/GRE Connecting Professors via Email After Application Contact Me Previous students advised Before You Read This will be a long article which will take you approximately about 15 minutes to read.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      
        <description>I believe having a good code repo is a necessary part of a good paper. You can find the source code for my papers and other interesting projects through my Github.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ninth Art</title>
      <link>/blog_posts/ninthart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog_posts/ninthart/</guid>
      
        <description>Thoughts on Red Deepemtion 2, GTA, Cypberpunk, Mafia, Borderland, Assain Creed, Split Fiction, It takes two, Tumber Raider, Civilization, OverWatch, HearthStone, Wolong, Resident Evil</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo Gallery</title>
      <link>/gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/gallery/</guid>
      
        <description>&amp;#x1f48f; With my beloved beautiful girl, Ziqi Li. &amp;#x2b50; With Professor Baochun Li, Professor Vincent Wong, and members of iQua on 2024 Engineering Institute of Canada (EIC) Gala.
&amp;#x1f4f7; by Mitch Lenet</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      
        <description>You can learn more about my papers through Google Scholar and OpenReview.
Privacy-Preserving Machine Learning Differential Privacy and Foundation Models Dixi Yao, Tian Li. &amp;ldquo;Differentially Private Retrieval Augmented Generation with Random Projection&amp;rdquo; in ICLR 2025 Workshop Building Trust in LLMs and LLM Applications: From Guardrails to Explainability to Regulation, Singapore, Apr 27 - Apr 28, 2025.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Interesting Stories during My Master</title>
      <link>/blog_posts/masterinteresting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog_posts/masterinteresting/</guid>
      
        <description>Some interesting stories during my master</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Pieces of Advices on Chossing Career Path</title>
      <link>/blog_posts/careerpath/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog_posts/careerpath/</guid>
      
        <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>